<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>The Elgeti Lab</title>
    <link>https://elgetilab.github.io/</link>
    <description>Recent content on The Elgeti Lab</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sat, 31 Dec 2022 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://elgetilab.github.io/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Mahdi B. Helabad</title>
      <link>https://elgetilab.github.io/people/mahdi/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 31 Dec 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://elgetilab.github.io/people/mahdi/</guid>
      <description>Mahdi is a computational biophysicist interested in understanding macromolecular interactions, structures, and dynamics, and how they relate to the function and behavior of biological systems. By utilizing computational methods in an integrative approach with experimental techniques such as NMR (mainly ssNMR) and DEER, he aims to gain a deeper understanding of the physical and chemical principles that govern the behavior of biological macromolecules. Specifically, he is interested in three different macromolecular systems: the sliding and search-to-recognition mechanism of transcription factors at the atomic level, the behavior of fibrillar aggregates with a focus on Huntington fibrils and their interactions with small molecules, and the biased agonism of G protein-coupled receptors (GPCRs) and their preferential signalling towards either G-proteins or β-arrestin.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Julia Belyaeva</title>
      <link>https://elgetilab.github.io/people/julia/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 31 Dec 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://elgetilab.github.io/people/julia/</guid>
      <description>Julia is currently finishing her master&amp;rsquo;s degree in Bioengineering and Bioinformatics at Lomonosov Moscow State University under the supervision of Dr. Andrey Golovin. She has also worked as a bioinformatician at BostonGene and Lactocore Inc on projects related to the development of cancer therapies and peptidic drugs targeted towards GPCRs, respectively. Julia will join the Elgeti Lab as a PhD student in the summer of 2023.
Julia&amp;rsquo;s research interests include the biology of GPCRs with a particular focus on their medical applications, the exploration of biomacromolecules’ conformational dynamics, and the development of antibacterial peptides that can help address the growing issue of antibiotic resistance.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Paula Kosel</title>
      <link>https://elgetilab.github.io/people/paula/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 31 Dec 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://elgetilab.github.io/people/paula/</guid>
      <description>Paula joined the Elgeti Lab as a Technical Assistant in Summer 2023 to learn more about the complex field of membrane proteins. She completed her bachelor&amp;rsquo;s degree in biology at the Martin Luther University Halle-Wittenberg (2019) and her master&amp;rsquo;s degree in biology at the University of Leipzig (2023).
During her studies, she gained practical experience in a variety of areas through various internships (Friedrich-Loeffler-Institute, Federal Research Institute for Animal Health, Alfred-Wegener-Institute Helmholtz Centre for Polar and Marine Research) and student assistantships (Max Planck Institute for Human Cognitive and Brain Science, Max Planck Institute for Evolutionary Anthropology).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Contact</title>
      <link>https://elgetilab.github.io/contact/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 25 Feb 2019 13:38:41 -0600</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://elgetilab.github.io/contact/</guid>
      <description>** Contact page don&amp;rsquo;t contain a body, just the front matter above. See form.html in the layouts folder.
Formspree requires a (free) account and new form to be set up. The link is made on the final published url in the field: Restrict to Domain. It is possible to register up to 2 emails free and you can select which one you want the forms to go to within Formspree in the Settings tab.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Join</title>
      <link>https://elgetilab.github.io/join/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://elgetilab.github.io/join/</guid>
      <description>Join Join the Elgeti Lab as we build our team!
Open positions Graduate student. Are you interested in protein design, hyperpolarization, and the development of new molecular sensors? Join Hyp*Mol, a new, collaborative, and interdisciplinary research program funded by the German Research Foundation. The open position is for a graduate (PhD) student, who will be mentored jointly by three PIs from Leipzig University (Matthias Elgeti, Irene Coin, and Jens Meiler.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>License</title>
      <link>https://elgetilab.github.io/license/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://elgetilab.github.io/license/</guid>
      <description>My blog posts are released under a Creative Commons Attribution-ShareAlike 4.0 International License.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Our research</title>
      <link>https://elgetilab.github.io/research/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://elgetilab.github.io/research/</guid>
      <description>Our research Proteins “at work” constantly change shape in order to interact with binding partners such as ligands or other proteins. Membrane proteins in particular exhibit a high degree of flexibility to control transmembrane signaling processes. In the Elgeti Lab, we utilize electron paramagnetic resonance (EPR) spectroscopy and other biophysical, biochemical, and computational methods to characterize and understand membrane proteins. Our research connects protein structure to function and contributes to the development of more efficacious therapeutics with fewer side effects.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Publications</title>
      <link>https://elgetilab.github.io/publications/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://elgetilab.github.io/publications/</guid>
      <description>Publications *co-first author, ‡corresponding author
Preprints Zhao J, Elgeti M*‡, O&amp;rsquo;Brien ES, Sár CP, Daibani AE, Heng J, Sun X, Che T, Hubbell WL, Kobilka BK, Chen C (2023). Conformational dynamics of the μ-opioid receptor determine ligand intrinsic efficacy. bioRxiv 2023.04.28.538657
Published Wygas MM, Laugwitz JM, Schmidt P, Elgeti M, Kaiser A. Dynamics of the Second Extracellular Loop Control Transducer Coupling of Peptide-Activated GPCRs. (2023). *International Journal of Molecular Sciences, 24 (15):*12197.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
