<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>The Elgeti Lab</title>
    <link>https://elgetilab.github.io/</link>
    <description>Recent content on The Elgeti Lab</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 25 Feb 2019 13:38:41 -0600</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://elgetilab.github.io/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Matthias Elgeti</title>
      <link>https://elgetilab.github.io/people/matthias/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://elgetilab.github.io/people/matthias/</guid>
      <description>Matthias received his PhD in Biophysics from the Humboldt Universitaet zu Berlin, where he worked under the guidance of Drs. Klaus Peter Hofmann and Franz Bartl on time-resolved investigation of photoreactions of visual rhodopsin. He then received postdoctoral training in the laboratory of Dr. Wayne Hubbell at UCLA, where he studied other G protein coupled receptors (GPCRs), such as the beta-adrenergic and angiotensin receptors, using electron paramagnetic resonance (EPR) spectroscopy.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Mahdi B. Helabad</title>
      <link>https://elgetilab.github.io/people/mahdi/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://elgetilab.github.io/people/mahdi/</guid>
      <description>Mahdi is a computational biophysicist interested in understanding macromolecular interactions, structures, and dynamics, and how they relate to the function and behavior of biological systems. By utilizing computational methods in an integrative approach with experimental techniques such as NMR (mainly ssNMR) and DEER, he aims to gain a deeper understanding of the physical and chemical principles that govern the behavior of biological macromolecules. Specifically, he is interested in three different macromolecular systems: the sliding and search-to-recognition mechanism of transcription factors at the atomic level, the behavior of fibrillar aggregates with a focus on Huntington fibrils and their interactions with small molecules, and the biased agonism of G protein-coupled receptors (GPCRs) and their preferential signalling towards either G-proteins or β-arrestin.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Julia Belyaeva</title>
      <link>https://elgetilab.github.io/people/julia/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://elgetilab.github.io/people/julia/</guid>
      <description>Julia joined the Elgeti Lab as a PhD student in the summer of 2023. She completed her master&amp;rsquo;s degree in Bioengineering and Bioinformatics at Lomonosov Moscow State University under the supervision of Dr. Andrey Golovin. She has also worked as a bioinformatician at BostonGene and Lactocore Inc on projects related to the development of cancer therapies and peptidic drugs targeted towards GPCRs, respectively.
Julia&amp;rsquo;s research interests include the biology of GPCRs with a particular focus on their medical applications, the exploration of biomacromolecules’ conformational dynamics, and the development of antibacterial peptides that can help address the growing issue of antibiotic resistance.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Sebastian Krebs</title>
      <link>https://elgetilab.github.io/people/sebastian/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://elgetilab.github.io/people/sebastian/</guid>
      <description>After finishing his master’s degree in biochemistry at the University of Leipzig under the supervision of Prof. Dr. Thorsten Berg, Sebastian joined the Life Science Technologies (LST) group at Bayer Pharmaceuticals as an intern. LST is part of the Drug Discovery Sciences department, with the ambition to understand complex biology and novel modalities. Sebastian joined the Elgeti lab as a PhD student in the November 2023.
Sebastian is working on the in silico design of a flavomaquette to study polarization transfer in biological systems.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Dilara Öğütcü</title>
      <link>https://elgetilab.github.io/people/dilara/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 01 Jan 1970 01:13:18 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://elgetilab.github.io/people/dilara/</guid>
      <description>Dilara joined the Elgeti Lab in the Winter semester of 2023. She completed her bachelor&amp;rsquo;s and master&amp;rsquo;s degrees in Biology at the Middle East Technical University in Turkey. She worked on adhesion GPCRs during her master&amp;rsquo;s study and subsequently gained experience in structural biology during her internship at the Rudolf Schönheimer Institute for Biochemistry at the University of Leipzig under the supervision of Dr. Sandra Berndt.
Dilara&amp;rsquo;s research is focused on understanding the dynamics of subtype selectivity on peptide receptors of GPCRs.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Paula Kosel</title>
      <link>https://elgetilab.github.io/people/paula/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://elgetilab.github.io/people/paula/</guid>
      <description>Paula joined the Elgeti Lab as a Technical Assistant in Summer 2023 to learn more about the complex field of membrane proteins. She completed her bachelor’s degree in biology at the Martin Luther University Halle-Wittenberg (2019) and her master’s degree in biology at the University of Leipzig (2023).
During her studies, she gained practical experience in a variety of areas through various internships (Friedrich-Loeffler-Institute, Federal Research Institute for Animal Health, Alfred-Wegener-Institute Helmholtz Centre for Polar and Marine Research) and student assistantships (Max Planck Institute for Human Cognitive and Brain Science, Max Planck Institute for Evolutionary Anthropology).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Martin Buhlmann</title>
      <link>https://elgetilab.github.io/people/martin/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 01 Jan 1970 01:08:20 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://elgetilab.github.io/people/martin/</guid>
      <description>Martin is a chemistry student who is currently working on his M.Sc. thesis in the Elgeti Lab.
Alongside his bachelor’s degree, he gained experience in organic synthesis at HPC Standards GmbH, where he worked as a student assistant. He is also taking part in the Advanced course of study in analytics and spectroscopy at the University of Leipzig.
His research topic is the investigation of the conformational landscape of the maltose-binding protein using EPR spectroscopy.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Contact</title>
      <link>https://elgetilab.github.io/contact/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 25 Feb 2019 13:38:41 -0600</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://elgetilab.github.io/contact/</guid>
      <description>** Contact page don&amp;rsquo;t contain a body, just the front matter above. See form.html in the layouts folder.
Formspree requires a (free) account and new form to be set up. The link is made on the final published url in the field: Restrict to Domain. It is possible to register up to 2 emails free and you can select which one you want the forms to go to within Formspree in the Settings tab.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Join</title>
      <link>https://elgetilab.github.io/join/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://elgetilab.github.io/join/</guid>
      <description>JoinJoin the Elgeti Lab as we build our team!
Open positionsThere are currently no open positions.
Other opportunitiesIf you are interested in joining the lab as a postdoctoral fellow, graduate student (Ph.D./M.Sc.), or student assistant, please contact Matthias.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>License</title>
      <link>https://elgetilab.github.io/license/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://elgetilab.github.io/license/</guid>
      <description>My blog posts are released under a Creative Commons Attribution-ShareAlike 4.0 International License.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>News</title>
      <link>https://elgetilab.github.io/news/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://elgetilab.github.io/news/</guid>
      <description>NewsNew review on structural modeling using EPR constraintsSeptember 16, 2024In preparation for Julia&amp;rsquo;s PhD work, we wrote a review about structural modeling using EPR constraints. It was very interesting and important to summarize what&amp;rsquo;s out there and which tools are missing. Today it&amp;rsquo;s finally out in eLife. (read online). Great job, Julia! Pharmacy Science Day 2024July 3, 2024Graduate students from the Elgeti lab presented their work at Leipzig University&amp;rsquo;s first Pharmacy Science Day.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Our research</title>
      <link>https://elgetilab.github.io/research/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://elgetilab.github.io/research/</guid>
      <description>Our researchProteins “at work” constantly change shape in order to interact with binding partners such as ligands or other proteins. Membrane proteins in particular exhibit a high degree of flexibility to control transmembrane signaling processes. In the Elgeti Lab, we utilize electron paramagnetic resonance (EPR) spectroscopy and other biophysical, biochemical, and computational methods to characterize and understand membrane proteins. Our research connects protein structure to function and contributes to the development of more efficacious therapeutics with fewer side effects.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Publications</title>
      <link>https://elgetilab.github.io/publications/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://elgetilab.github.io/publications/</guid>
      <description>Publications*co-first author, ‡corresponding author
Belyaeva J, Elgeti M‡. Exploring protein structural ensembles: Integration of sparse experimental data from electron paramagnetic resonance spectroscopy with molecular modeling methods. (2024). eLife, 13: e99770. read online
Zhao J, Elgeti M*‡, O&amp;rsquo;Brien ES, Sár CP, El Daibani A, Heng J, Sun X, Che T, Hubbell WL, Kobilka BK, Chen C. Ligand efficacy modulates conformational dynamics of the μ-opioid receptor. (2024). Nature, 629: 474-480. read online | preprint</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
