<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>The Elgeti Lab</title>
    <link>https://elgetilab.github.io/</link>
    <description>Recent content on The Elgeti Lab</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 25 Feb 2019 13:38:41 -0600</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://elgetilab.github.io/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Matthias Elgeti</title>
      <link>https://elgetilab.github.io/people/matthias/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://elgetilab.github.io/people/matthias/</guid>
      <description>Matthias received his PhD in Biophysics from the Humboldt Universitaet zu Berlin, where he worked under the guidance of Drs. Klaus Peter Hofmann and Franz Bartl on time-resolved investigation of photoreactions of visual rhodopsin. He then received postdoctoral training in the laboratory of Dr. Wayne Hubbell at UCLA, where he studied other G protein coupled receptors (GPCRs), such as the beta-adrenergic and angiotensin receptors, using electron paramagnetic resonance (EPR) spectroscopy.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Julia Belyaeva</title>
      <link>https://elgetilab.github.io/people/julia/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://elgetilab.github.io/people/julia/</guid>
      <description>Julia joined the Elgeti Lab as a PhD student in the summer of 2023. She completed her master&amp;rsquo;s degree in Bioengineering and Bioinformatics at Lomonosov Moscow State University. She has also worked as a bioinformatician at BostonGene and Lactocore Inc on projects related to the development of cancer therapies and peptidic drugs targeted towards GPCRs, respectively.
Now she is working on developing an integrative computational approach to model rare conformations of GPCRs from sparse experimental DEER data.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Martin Buhlmann</title>
      <link>https://elgetilab.github.io/people/martin/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 01 Jan 1970 01:08:20 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://elgetilab.github.io/people/martin/</guid>
      <description>Martin completed his M.Sc. in Chemistry at the University of Leipzig in September 2024, where he conducted his master’s thesis research in the Elgeti Lab. He has since joined the lab as a PhD student.
Alongside his studies, Martin gained hands-on experience in organic synthesis as a student assistant at HPC Standards GmbH. In addition, he successfully completed the &amp;ldquo;Advanced Course of Study in Analytics and Spectroscopy&amp;rdquo; at the University of Leipzig in September 2024.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Markus Fischer</title>
      <link>https://elgetilab.github.io/people/markus/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://elgetilab.github.io/people/markus/</guid>
      <description>Markus is a physicist by training who earned his master’s degree at TU Chemnitz, where he worked on Ornstein–Uhlenbeck processes. He later obtained his PhD at the Institute of Medical Physics under the supervision of Dr. Holger Scheidt, focusing on membrane interactions of small molecules and GNN-based interaction predictions.
After completing his PhD, he worked in IT consulting before returning to academia by joining the Elgeti Lab in December 2024.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Sebastian Krebs</title>
      <link>https://elgetilab.github.io/people/sebastian/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://elgetilab.github.io/people/sebastian/</guid>
      <description>After finishing his master’s degree in biochemistry at the University of Leipzig under the supervision of Prof. Dr. Thorsten Berg, Sebastian joined the Life Science Technologies (LST) group at Bayer Pharmaceuticals as an intern. LST is part of the Drug Discovery Sciences department, with the ambition to understand complex biology and novel modalities. Sebastian joined the Elgeti lab as a PhD student in the November 2023.
Sebastian is working on the in silico design of a flavomaquette to study polarization transfer in biological systems.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Dilara Öğütcü</title>
      <link>https://elgetilab.github.io/people/dilara/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 01 Jan 1970 01:13:18 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://elgetilab.github.io/people/dilara/</guid>
      <description>Dilara joined the Elgeti Lab in the Winter semester of 2023. She completed her bachelor&amp;rsquo;s and master&amp;rsquo;s degrees in Biology at the Middle East Technical University in Turkey. She worked on adhesion GPCRs during her master&amp;rsquo;s study and subsequently gained experience in structural biology during her internship at the Rudolf Schönheimer Institute for Biochemistry at the University of Leipzig under the supervision of Dr. Sandra Berndt.
Dilara&amp;rsquo;s research is focused on understanding the dynamics of subtype selectivity on peptide receptors of GPCRs.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Ivan Yushin</title>
      <link>https://elgetilab.github.io/people/ivan/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 01 Jan 1970 01:08:20 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://elgetilab.github.io/people/ivan/</guid>
      <description>Ivan Yushin joined the Elgeti lab in January 2025 as Ph.D. student after finishing his Specialist degree in Chemistry at Novosibirsk State University, where he worked on structure and thermodynamics of DNA complexes.
For his Ph.D. Ivan is integrating cutting-edge 3D printing technology with EPR spectroscopy and computational modeling, to facilitate screening of novel drug molecules.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Patricia Schmidt</title>
      <link>https://elgetilab.github.io/people/patricia/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://elgetilab.github.io/people/patricia/</guid>
      <description>Patricia joined the Elgeti Lab as a PhD student in fall 2025, following her M.Sc. in Biochemistry at the University of Leipzig.
Her doctoral research will integrate EPR spectroscopy with computational approaches to investigate the conformational dynamics of arrestins and how these shape their diverse downstream signaling pathways.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Anna Krauspe</title>
      <link>https://elgetilab.github.io/people/anna/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://elgetilab.github.io/people/anna/</guid>
      <description>During her Master’s studies in the Elgeti Lab, Anna developed a novel ligand-binding assay using CW EPR. We are excited that she will continue with us as our lab manager. With her strong background in biochemistry, her positive mindset, and her eagerness to master new techniques, Anna will be an invaluable support to all ongoing and future projects.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Contact</title>
      <link>https://elgetilab.github.io/contact/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 25 Feb 2019 13:38:41 -0600</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://elgetilab.github.io/contact/</guid>
      <description>** Contact page don&amp;rsquo;t contain a body, just the front matter above. See form.html in the layouts folder.
Formspree requires a (free) account and new form to be set up. The link is made on the final published url in the field: Restrict to Domain. It is possible to register up to 2 emails free and you can select which one you want the forms to go to within Formspree in the Settings tab.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Alumni</title>
      <link>https://elgetilab.github.io/alumni/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://elgetilab.github.io/alumni/</guid>
      <description>AlumniDr. Mahdi Bagherpoor Helabad
Paula Kosel</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Join</title>
      <link>https://elgetilab.github.io/join/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://elgetilab.github.io/join/</guid>
      <description>Join the Elgeti Lab as we build our team!Open positionsOpen Bachelor’s or Master’s Thesis OpportunityWe are looking for motivated students (Biology, Biochemistry, Chemistry, or Physics) to join our team for a Bachelor’s or Master’s thesis within the HYP*MOL Collaborative Research Center, which focuses on hyperpolarization in molecular systems.
Our project investigates a flavin-binding protein that forms a light-induced spin-correlated radical pair (SCRP). We aim to uncover how this radical pair is generated and how spin polarization is transferred, with the long-term goal of controlling and optimizing these processes to create a novel protein-based spin tag.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>License</title>
      <link>https://elgetilab.github.io/license/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://elgetilab.github.io/license/</guid>
      <description>My blog posts are released under a Creative Commons Attribution-ShareAlike 4.0 International License.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>News</title>
      <link>https://elgetilab.github.io/news/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://elgetilab.github.io/news/</guid>
      <description>NewsMarkus’ Project Funded by the Hyp*MOL ConsortiumNovember 4-7, 2025Markus needs serious GPU power to train his graph neural networks — so he applied for funding from the Hyp*MOL consortium to build our own mini-cluster.His proposal was very well received and has been fully funded!At this year’s Hyp*MOL status meeting, Markus presented the background and current progress of his project to the community. Great job, Markus — way to go!</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Our research</title>
      <link>https://elgetilab.github.io/research/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://elgetilab.github.io/research/</guid>
      <description>Our researchProteins “at work” constantly change shape in order to interact with binding partners such as ligands or other proteins. Membrane proteins in particular exhibit a high degree of flexibility to control transmembrane signaling processes. In the Elgeti Lab, we utilize electron paramagnetic resonance (EPR) spectroscopy and other biophysical, biochemical, and computational methods to characterize and understand membrane proteins. Our research connects protein structure to function and contributes to the development of more efficacious therapeutics with fewer side effects.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Publications</title>
      <link>https://elgetilab.github.io/publications/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://elgetilab.github.io/publications/</guid>
      <description>Publications*co-first author, ‡corresponding author
Elgeti M‡, Belyaeva J*, Bagherpoor Helabad M, Staus DP, Wingler LM‡. Angiotensin receptor conformations stabilized by biased ligands differentially modulate β-arrestin interactions. (2025). Under review preprint
Gupta V, Laugwitz J, Sklodowski M, Voitel M, Sala D, Kaiser A, Elgeti M, Meiler J, Huster D, Beck-Sickinger AG, Schmidt P, Penk A. Structural insights into the binding modes of arrestin-3 finger loop to the neuropeptide Y1 and Y2 receptors.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
